<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>eye gaze | Academic</title><link>https://geyiping.github.io/tag/eye-gaze/</link><atom:link href="https://geyiping.github.io/tag/eye-gaze/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>eye gaze</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 04:54:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://geyiping.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>eye gaze</title><link>https://geyiping.github.io/tag/eye-gaze/</link></image><item><title>Gaze-mediated fear transmission modulates perception of temporal duration</title><link>https://geyiping.github.io/project/gaze-mediated-fear-transmission-modulates-perception-of-temporal-duration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 04:54:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geyiping.github.io/project/gaze-mediated-fear-transmission-modulates-perception-of-temporal-duration/</guid><description>&lt;p>Both inherent fear attributes and newly acquired fear information have been found to affect time perception, inducing a time extension effect. Building upon the foundation of previous studies (Bar-Haim et al., 2010; Grommet et al., 2011; Tipples, 2008; Fayolle et al., 2015; Kliegl et al., 2015), this study aims to explore whether fear learning mediated by eye gaze can similarly influence perceptual processing, specifically, perception of temporal duration. Additionally, considering the importance of intention transmission in processing eye gaze cues, we also investigate whether socially relevant autistic traits, linked to impaired intention processing (Baron-Cohen et al., 2001), modulate gaze-mediated fear learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study employs a &amp;ldquo;three-phase&amp;rdquo; experimental paradigm. During the intermediate learning phase, fear transmission toward previously neutral cartoon faces via gaze cues was conducted using a modified central cue paradigm. Pre- and post-tests utilized time perception tasks to examine whether the fearful attributes conveyed by eye gaze during intermediate learning led to changes in individual subjective temporal perception.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, Exp.1 explored whether gaze-mediated fear transmission biases subjective perception of temporal duration, and whether there exists a modulating role of autistic traits. In Exp. 2, a novel cartoon face stimuli was introduced as a control to investigate whether the effect of gaze-mediated fear learning on time perception, if observed, is more attributed to fearful gaze association rather than non-association. In Exp. 3, the baffle images were introduced to obstruct gaze cues from &amp;lsquo;seeing&amp;rsquo; cartoon faces to explore whether such effects are influenced by perception of intention conveyance. （The picture on this page comes from the Internet）&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fear properties transmitted via eye gaze: a new way to acquire affective attitudes through the social channel</title><link>https://geyiping.github.io/project/gaze1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 13:39:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geyiping.github.io/project/gaze1/</guid><description>&lt;p>The pivotal role of eye gaze as a fundamental social cue is distinctly evident within the framework of social fear acquisition. Here we specifically explore its intermediary function within this process and unveil a gaze-mediated fear transmission. By employing a novel gaze-associated learning paradigm in conjunction with affective priming tasks, we showed that fearful-gaze-associated cartoon faces induced a discernible negative shift in affective dispositions compared with those associated with the non-fearful gaze. Notably, this fear transmission was not attributed to general attentional allocation or driven by low-level visual information, since it disappeared under conditions of gaze inversion. Critically, the gaze-mediated fear transmission vanished when cues were obstructed by baffles, implying the key role of intention processing elicited by eye gaze during the fear acquisition. Moreover, invisible gaze cues could also mediate and impose fear properties onto previously neutral cartoon faces, which suggests that gaze-mediated fear transmission exists even without conscious awareness. In summary, our findings emphasize the profound social implications of eye gaze and shed new light on the nuanced dynamics of affective attitude acquisition and calibration in interpersonal interactions.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>