<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fear learning | Yiping Ge's Web</title><link>https://geyiping.github.io/tag/fear-learning/</link><atom:link href="https://geyiping.github.io/tag/fear-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>fear learning</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 13:39:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://geyiping.github.io/media/icon_hu1fa361f8cfe53b7d5c04919ce5e69227_9290_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>fear learning</title><link>https://geyiping.github.io/tag/fear-learning/</link></image><item><title>Fear properties transmitted via eye gaze: a new way to acquire affective attitudes through the social channel</title><link>https://geyiping.github.io/project/gaze1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 13:39:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geyiping.github.io/project/gaze1/</guid><description>&lt;p>The pivotal role of eye gaze as a fundamental social cue is distinctly evident within the framework of social fear acquisition. Here we specifically explore its intermediary function within this process and unveil a gaze-mediated fear transmission. By employing a novel gaze-associated learning paradigm in conjunction with affective priming tasks, we showed that fearful-gaze-associated cartoon faces induced a discernible negative shift in affective dispositions compared with those associated with the non-fearful gaze. Notably, this fear transmission was not attributed to general attentional allocation or driven by low-level visual information, since it disappeared under conditions of gaze inversion. Critically, the gaze-mediated fear transmission vanished when cues were obstructed by baffles, implying the key role of intention processing elicited by eye gaze during the fear acquisition. Moreover, invisible gaze cues could also mediate and impose fear properties onto previously neutral cartoon faces, which suggests that gaze-mediated fear transmission exists even without conscious awareness. In summary, our findings emphasize the profound social implications of eye gaze and shed new light on the nuanced dynamics of affective attitude acquisition and calibration in interpersonal interactions.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>