<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>time peception | Yiping Ge's Web</title><link>https://geyiping.github.io/tag/time-peception/</link><atom:link href="https://geyiping.github.io/tag/time-peception/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>time peception</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 04:54:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://geyiping.github.io/media/icon_hue2d01be14f5c2e7687fa13e65aba3e75_5388_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>time peception</title><link>https://geyiping.github.io/tag/time-peception/</link></image><item><title>Gaze-mediated fear transmission modulates perception of temporal duration</title><link>https://geyiping.github.io/project/gaze-mediated-fear-transmission-modulates-perception-of-temporal-duration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 04:54:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geyiping.github.io/project/gaze-mediated-fear-transmission-modulates-perception-of-temporal-duration/</guid><description>&lt;p>Both inherent fear attributes and newly acquired fear information have been found to affect time perception, inducing a time extension effect. Building upon the foundation of previous studies (Bar-Haim et al., 2010; Grommet et al., 2011; Tipples, 2008; Fayolle et al., 2015; Kliegl et al., 2015), this study aims to explore whether fear learning mediated by eye gaze can similarly influence perceptual processing, specifically, perception of temporal duration. Additionally, considering the importance of intention transmission in processing eye gaze cues, we also investigate whether socially relevant autistic traits, linked to impaired intention processing (Baron-Cohen et al., 2001), modulate gaze-mediated fear learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This study employs a &amp;ldquo;three-phase&amp;rdquo; experimental paradigm. During the intermediate learning phase, fear transmission toward previously neutral cartoon faces via gaze cues was conducted using a modified central cue paradigm. Pre- and post-tests utilized time perception tasks to examine whether the fearful attributes conveyed by eye gaze during intermediate learning led to changes in individual subjective temporal perception.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, Exp.1 explored whether gaze-mediated fear transmission biases subjective perception of temporal duration, and whether there exists a modulating role of autistic traits. In Exp. 2, a novel cartoon face stimuli was introduced as a control to investigate whether the effect of gaze-mediated fear learning on time perception, if observed, is more attributed to fearful gaze association rather than non-association. In Exp. 3, the baffle images were introduced to obstruct gaze cues from &amp;lsquo;seeing&amp;rsquo; cartoon faces to explore whether such effects are influenced by perception of intention conveyance. （The picture on this page comes from the Internet）&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>